远鉴字幕组制作
[Visionary] 0day-sub
翻译&校对：william2568
欢迎来到比肯镇 这是一个奇妙而活跃的小镇
Welcome to Suburbicon, a town of great wonder and excitement.
始建于1947年的
Founded in 1947,
比肯镇寄托了人们共同富裕的愿望
Suburbicon was built with the promise of prosperity for all.
仅仅12年后 它从几座小屋
And in only 12 short years, it has grown from a few small homes
发展成为一个生机勃勃的社区
to a living, breathing community
这里的生活像大城市一样方便
with all the conveniences of the big city
但却不会受到噪音和交通堵塞的困扰
without all the noise or the traffic.
现在这里有近六万名居民
And now, with nearly 60,000 residents,
配有学校
they enjoy their own schools,
消防部门
a fire department,
警察局
and a police department.
购物中心
There's a shopping mall.
一流的医院
A first-rate hospital.
甚至还有自发组织的合唱团
Why, we even have our own choir.
小镇的居民来自我们伟大祖国的各个地方
The people of Suburbicon hail from all corners of this great nation.
这里就像大熔炉 人口富有多样性 就像..
A melting pot of diversity from cities as far away as...
纽约城那样
New york!
还像..俄亥俄州
And... Ohio!
- 还像... - 密西西比州
- And even...  - Mississippi!
小镇目前只缺一样东西 那就是您的大驾光临
The only thing Suburbicon is missing is you.
现在难道不是 您开始崭新生活的最佳时机么
Isn't it time for your new start?
来比肯镇定居吧
Come home to Suburbicon.
- 嘿 特克斯 - 我在骑双轮车呢
- Hey there, Tex! - I'm two-wheelin' it!
哟 你有骑车的驾照么 - 他现在还没撞坏东西呢
He got a license for that? - He ain't broke nothin' yet.
再让他骑一小时 他肯定就会撞坏东西了
Well, give him an hour. He'll break something.
彭德尔顿夫人
Mrs. Pendelton.
小心点 亨利 我们才卸下辅助轮不久呢
Watch yourself, Henry. We just took his wheels off.
你有没有拜访一下你的新邻居
Say, have you met your neighbor yet?
还没呢 他们昨晚搬进来的 我在给他们做蛋挞
No, they just moved in last night, but I'm baking them a custard.
不错啊
Mmm, boy!
- 伙计们好 - 先生好
Hey, fellows. - Sir.
这里是公用事业的清单 订购新一期的
Here we go. Got all the utilities and a new subscription
家政服务 迈尔斯夫人在么
to good housekeeping. Is Mrs. Mayers about?
我就是迈尔斯夫人
I'm Mrs. Mayers.
好啊
Well, all right!
欢迎来到比肯小镇 祝您在这生活愉快
Uh, welcome to Suburbicon. Hope you enjoy your stay.
那是我家的信么
Is that our mail?
噢..抱歉
Oh... Sorry.
您有没有拜访一下你的新邻居
Have you met your new neighbor?
把那个放到安迪的房间 这个放到客厅 谢谢
You can put that in Andy's room, and that goes in the living room. Thank you.
安静
Calm down!
安静 我听不到你们 我听不到...
Hey, come on, I can't hear you! I can't...
一个个说 好么
One at a time, one at a time! Right?
查克 你先说
Chuck! Chuck!
我们不想让他们住这
We don't want 'em here.
我想问问在座的各位 谁觉得不介意他们住这的
Can I ask who thought this'd be all right?
- 我认为我们的社区能包容他们一家的 - 不是我们 是你
Well, I think we thought that the community would tolerate them. - Not we. Him!
你能忍?
You?
冷静 我们找小镇负责人谈过了
Quiet down. We've spoken with the city planners,
迈尔斯家的周围的房屋会用来阻挡他们家的视野
and the adjacent homes will be supplied fencing to block the view of the Mayers.
那谁来为这开销掏钱呢
And who's gonna pay for that?
我们住房委员会付钱 杰克逊
We'll pay for it, Jackson. The housing committee.
我们可不会为这掏钱的
'Cause we ain't gonna pay for it.
他妈的 谁说让你付钱了
You're not gonna pay for it, god damn it!
- 我们拿他们也没什么办法啊 - 我们能做些什么的
But there's not much we can do about these folks. - Oh, we can do something about it.
詹姆斯 读一下请愿书
James, read the petition.
支持迈尔斯一家留下的人说我们的恐惧是毫无根据的 我们驳斥这种观点
"We defy the supporters of Mr. Mayers to say our fears are groundless.
我们支持种族融合
"We favor racial integration,
但是只有这帮黑鬼准备好了 我们才会开始这么做
"but only at such time the negro shows he's ready for it.
他们不求上进
"They don't seek to better themselves.
我们的社区已经在错误的道路上
"This community has come too far
越走越远了
to move backwards.
我们要求行使我们的权力
"We demand our civil rights
我们要自己决定要跟谁住在一起
"to live where we want and with whom we want,
上帝会帮助我们 我们一定能克服所有的困难
"and, with god's help, we will overcome!"
你们还记得巴尔的摩 特伦顿发生的事么
You remember what happened in Baltimore? And Trenton?
这就是为什么人们选择搬到这里
That's why people moved here.
沃尔科特家的人说我们的房产价值会缩水
The wolcotts said all our property values will drop.
就算我们想把房子卖了 也卖不出去
So even if we wanted to sell, we can't.
我的天 萝丝
Oh, for heaven sakes, Rose.
要是房产价值缩水 也是这帮沃尔科特家的人搞的鬼
If anybody, it's those wolcotts that bring down property values.
这是一座平和的小镇
This is a peaceful town.
出了这种事 人们就沸腾了
People get crazy over things like this.
尼基 小宝贝 快过来
Nicky, sweetheart, come here.
亲爱的 迈尔斯家也有像你这么大的一个小男孩 他在门廊那儿呢
Honey, that Mayers family's got a little boy your age up there on that porch.
你怎么不去那
Why don't you hop on over there
找他一起去玩排球呢
and take him for baseball?
妈妈 我一定要去找他么
Mom, do I have to?
别看我
Don't look at me.
尼基 你去找那黑人小男孩 一起玩排球
Nicky! You take that little colored boy and play him some baseball.
你妈妈和我把这些扁豆搞定
Your mom and I are gonna finish these beans,
待会给你做一些黄油饼干
and then we'll make you some butter cookies for after.
去吧 去吧
Go on. Go on.
我不想玩排球
I don't want to play baseball.
嘿
Hey!
Hey.
你会玩排球么
You play baseball?
会
Yep.
他们在那拿撒勒教堂后面玩排球
They play out behind the Nazarene church.
我们不是拿撒勒派的
We ain't Nazarene.
我们是圣公会教徒
We're episcopalian.
那好吧
All right then.
你喜欢玩排球么 - 喜欢
You like baseball? - Yeah.
很喜欢么
You like it?
蟋蟀听到了
The crickets were listening.
夜空倾听者她的倾诉
The night was listening to her.
突然有一道声音
Then there was a sound!
一只土拨鼠拨弄着一块空心的圆木
Only a woodchuck, surely, beating a hollow log.
不 不 那是拉维妮亚·奈布斯
No. No, it was Lavinia Nebbs.
那绝对是拉维妮亚·奈布斯的心跳声
It was most surely the heart of Lavinia Nebbs.
她走下楼梯 越走越快 跑下楼梯
And she went down the steps, faster, faster, running now down the steps,
冲的越来越快 冲进峡谷里的一个深坑里
Plunging faster and faster, Down, down into the pit of the ravine.
就差一点了
Only a little way.
过桥 快跑
Across the bridge. Run.
快跑 别回头 别看他
Run. Don't turn. Don't look.
看到他你就动不了了
If you see him, you'll not be able to move!
跑就行了
You just run!
一条小路 群山之间 小路已尽 那条街道
Up the path, between the hills, the top of the path, the street.
虽然有亮光 恐惧...
And even with the light, the fear swirled a...
尼基 起床了
Nicky, you need to get up.
家里有人来了
There are men in the house.
快来 快来
Come on. Come on.
他们会拿走想要的东西 然后离开
They're gonna take what they want and leave.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be fine.
别坐在那张椅子上
Get the hell out of that chair.
闭嘴
Shut up.
给我拿杯喝的来
Get me a drink.
玛格丽特
Maggie.
要用托盘盛过来
On a tray.
给我也用托盘盛饮料过来
Give me a drink on a tray, too.
好了
All right.
我们能不能别在这折腾了
Look, can we just get this over with?
着急什么 跟别人有约么
What's the hurry? Got an appointment?
这就对了嘛
That's right.
别浪费时间了 开始吧
Let's quit fucking around and go.
来吧 女士
Come on, lady.
用手搂着我的脖子
Just put your arms around my neck.
- 我们走 - 我来吧
Here we go. I'll do that.
她不介意我来的
She don't mind.
你不介意吧 女士
You don't mind, do you, ma'am?
不介意
No.
这就对了 她不介意
That's right. She don't mind.
厕所在哪
Where's the toilet?
在走廊那边 你左手边
Um, it's... it's down the hall. Up to your left.
- 你有小儿麻痹症 - 什么
You got polio? - What?
- 小儿麻痹 - 她遭遇过车祸
Polio. - She was in a car accident.
真惨
Shit.
- 有人死了么 - 你是不是有什么毛病
Anybody die? - What is wrong with you?
我这是在了解一下情况
Just getting the lay of the land.
我想知道我面前的这位是不是一位杀人犯
Want to know if I'm talking to a killer.
- 她不是.. - 我丈夫开的车
She wasn't... - My husband was driving.
没人丧命
But no one died.
是啊 没什么大碍
Yeah. It all worked out just fine.
我们走吧
Let's get moving.
快出来 我操
Coming! Fuck!
霎时间 配角演员的名字
In just a moment, the names of the supporting players,
下周的故事充满悬念
and a word about next week's story of suspense.
我们说好了的 只要我们合作 就不会有危险
Now, we had an agreement that if we cooperate, no harm will come to us.
这个嘛
Well,
危险这个东西嘛 你无法预知它的到来
harm is one of those things you can't never tell about in advance.
至少我的经验是这样的
Least that's been my experience, far as it goes.
你可能比我还更清楚这个
But you probably know more about that than me.
你肯定觉得我们是变态
You must think we're pretty sick, huh?
禽兽不如
Couple animals.
你是这么觉得的吧
Is that what you think?
是啊 你是这么觉得的
Yeah. That's what you think.
你们那边的几位挺安静啊
You're pretty quiet over there.
你们是怎么看待这个问题的
What do you think about all this?
我觉得你们肯定不会伤害我们的
I'm sure that you won't hurt us.
女士
Lady,
你现在的处境 不存在肯定这么一说
you ain't in a position to be sure about anything.
- 这孩子你们也要绑起来么 - 我的天
Do you have to tie him up? No! Ow. Ow. Jesus chriSt.
自己稍微想想 这不是很明显么
Think about it for a minute. It's a question that answers itself.
我们快点搞定这个吧
Let's just get this over with.
你们这么紧张干什么 他只是个小孩子
What are you so fucking nervous about? He's just a little boy!
我们从这位阿姨开始 - 让她闭嘴
We'll start with the auntie over here. - Shut up her yappin'.
阿姨 阿姨
"Auntie em! Auntie em..."
放松 呼吸
Just breathe normal.
很好
Good.
我他妈的真喜欢那部电影
I love that fucking movie.
没事的 尼基 - 不 不 爸爸
Okay. Okay, Nicky. - No! No! Dad! Dad!
我来搞定这孩子
I'll do the kid.
别吵 小子
Settle down, kid.
这是一场不错的派对
It's gonna be a party.
氯仿是一种
Chloroform is
渐进型抑制剂 一般用于发动机
a progressive depressant. It works on the motors.
有短暂的麻醉效果
Usually just has a temporary narcotic effect,
显然
but, obviously,
你的妻子吸入了太多气体
your wife respired a lot more of the stuff,
器官正在衰竭
and her organs are failing.
尼基 亲爱的 我们很担心你
Nicky! Honey, we were so worried about you.
儿子
Son.
能听到我么
Can you hear me?
我们有一件事要告诉你
There's something I have to tell you.
非常伤心的事
It's something very sad.
全能的天神 我们已逝去的妹妹 萝丝
Unto almighty god, we commend the soul of Rose, our sister departed,
我们把她的肉体埋入地底
and we commit her body to the ground.
尘归尘 土归土
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
满怀复活的希望 直到生命永恒
In sure and certain hope of the resurrection unto eternal life
借我们的主耶稣基督再次降临
through our lord jesus christ.
如果你们需要什么 不要犹豫 马上联系我
If there's anything you need, don't hesitate to call me.
萝丝是一个坚强的女人
Rose was a very brave woman.
是的
Yes.
- 来吧 尼基 我们俩走一走 - 好的 先生
Come on, Nicky. Let's you and me take a walk. - Yes, sir.
她深爱着你和你的爸爸 - 谢谢
She loved you both very much. - Thank you.
圣公会教徒 都是一群混蛋
Episcopalians, they're all full of shit.
总有一天你会理解的 相信我
Someday, you'll understand. Meantime, you take my word for it.
我会的 米奇叔叔
I will, uncle Mitch.
我知道 目前你的前景
I know right now your path,
十分暗淡
it looks pretty bleak.
你的妈妈去世了 这挺让人难过的
Your ma's dead, and that, that's tough.
我也很难过 我自己的妹妹走了
Tough for me, too. My own sister.
但你不能就一直这么一言不发
But you can't just button up,
板着一张脸 就像你妈妈出了出了车祸时那样
pull a long face, like your ma did after her accident.
好的 米奇叔叔
Yes, uncle Mitch.
真是个好孩子
Attaboy.
现在回答我 谁把你当亲儿子一样看待
Now, who loves you like a son?
- 我爸 - 你这傻孩子 还有谁
Daddy does. - Who else, you little shit?
你 米奇叔叔
You do, uncle Mitch.
谁往你口袋里
Who lets you keep all the coins
放了那么多铜板零钱啊
that'll stay in your pockets, huh?
是你 米奇叔叔
You do, uncle Mitch.
上来
Come on!
孩子
Attaboy.
丫的 孩子你挺沉啊
Damn, you weigh a fucking ton, kid.
我的天
Damn it.
能不能让你这位兄弟正常一点
Just once I'd like to see your brother show some sense.
上车吧 米奇
Come on, Mitch.
好 等我一下 玛格丽特
All right. Hold your horses, maggie.
尼基 我们觉得
Nicky, we've decided it'd be best
让你阿姨玛格丽特和我们待一段时间比较好
if your auntie Margaret came and stayed with us for a while.
你应该也觉得不错吧
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
说真的 要是我生意不忙 我也会留下
Swear to god, I didn't have a business to run, I'd stay, too.
你想他来么 儿子
Would you like that, son?
他经历了太多 现在不想说话
He's had a bad shock. He doesn't want to talk right now.
给他一点时间缓缓
He just needs some time.
我跟你说点事 加德纳
I tell you something, Gardner.
要是让我抓到那些害死萝丝的混蛋
I ever get my hands on the cocksuckers that did that to Rosie,
我要扒了他们皮 从他们的屁眼里掏出他们的内脏
I'm gonna peel 'em back from their assholes, turn 'em inside out,
把他们肠子都拉出来 看他们喷血
so their guts are hanging out and they're pissing blood...
够了 米奇
Mitch!
不说了
All right.
他们服务的怎么样
What was with that service?
你阿姨睡楼上
Your aunt will sleep upstairs.
我就待楼下
And I'll stay down here.
我们能挺过来的 儿子
We'll be fine, son.
我们要坚强
We'll be strong.
我是不是懦夫
Coward, am I?
我为了你 竭尽全力和约翰·菲利普斗争
I fought for you with John Phillips all I can.
你都没骨气为了你自己..
You're not even man enough to fight your own...
甜味腌制火腿 提前煮好 方便食用
Sugar-cured ham. Pre-cooked. Ready to serve.
你可以前往你最爱的食品店购买此商品
And you can pick them up at your favorite food store.
尼基
Nicky!
嘿
Hey.
你妈妈去世了?
Your mama died?
是的
Yeah.
她上天堂了么
She go to heaven?
估计是吧
I guess.
我抓了条小蛇 想看看么
I got a ground snake. You want to see?
它会咬人么
Does it bite?
不会 他没牙齿呢
Nah. He ain't got no teeth.
送给你了
You can have it.
它吃什么
What's it eat?
蚂蚱 蟋蟀
Grasshopper or cricket.
我那有一玻璃罐的昆虫
I got a mason jar full of 'em.
它叫什么名字
What's its name?
它没有名字 它是条蛇
He ain't got no name. He's a snake.
你留着它吧
You keep it.
我来抓虫给它吃
I'll get them bugs.
爸爸
Dad?
尼基
Nicky.
你在那呆了多久了
How long have you been there?
玛格丽特
Maggie.
- 亲爱的 怎么了 - 他做噩梦了
What's the matter, angel? - He had a nightmare.
你阿姨会送你回去睡觉
Maggie will put you to bed.
没事的 小宝贝
It's all right, sweetheart.
尼基 不用再害怕了
There's nothing to be afraid of anymore, Nicky.
我知道
I know.
你知道这是什么吗
Do you know who this is?
这是圣帕特里克
This is St. Patrick.
他是你的主保圣人 你知道么
He's your patron saint. Did you know that?
不知道
No.
他是所有爱尔兰人的主保圣人
He's the patron saint of all the Irish.
但我不是爱尔兰人
But I'm not Irish.
你当然是了
Sure you are.
你的祖父是一位来自戈尔韦的造船工
Your grandfather was a shipbuilder from Galway.
每天他向圣帕特里克祈祷
And every day he'd pray to St. Patrick for the bride of his dreams.
然后他来到了美国 遇到了你的祖母
And then he came to america, and he met your grandmother.
他们一起为家人祈祷
And together they prayed for a family.
圣帕特里克保佑着你的妈妈 你的米奇叔叔 还有我
And St. Patrick blessed them with your mother and your uncle Mitch and me.
你的妈妈向圣帕特里克祈祷 保佑你
And then your mom prayed to St. Patrick for you.
是么  - 是的
She did? Mmm-hmm.
那我们现在是不是应该为你妈妈祈祷
Should we pray for your mom now?
好
Okay.
愿圣帕特里克的光照亮你的心底
May the light of St. Patrick find a place in your heart
提醒我们所爱之人终有一日要离去
and remind us that loved ones must someday depart.
愿他们轻柔的走过金黄的麦地
May their journey be gentle through gold fields of rye.
抚慰悲痛 爱意不止
And our sorrow be silenced, and our love never die.
- 阿门 - 阿门
Amen. - Amen.
玛格丽特 真是太糟了
Margaret, it's awful.
你们失去了一位至亲
It's such a loss.
萝丝接受了神启 耶稣与她同在
Rose was an inspiration. She's with jesus now.
谢谢各位女士
Thank you, ladies.
为萝丝祈祷
Pray for Rose.
这里从来都没发生过这样的事
Nothing like this ever happened here.
这是个安全的地方 - 那是以前了
This is a safe place. It was.
- 她很年轻 - 他们还生了一个儿子吧
Well, she's very young. - And he has a kid with her?
加德纳 欢迎回来
Gardner. Welcome back.
听到你的至亲离去 十分惋惜
Sorry to hear about your loss.
谢谢 罗杰
Thanks, Roger.
加德纳 这位是比尔·撒克里 新的客户经理
Gardner, this is Bill thackery, a new account executive.
比尔 这位是加德纳·洛奇 财务副总裁
Bill, this is Gardner Lodge, financial vp.
很高兴见到你
Glad to meet you.
- 我也很高兴 很抱歉不能在更愉快的场合认识你 - 真是不幸啊
Likewise. Sorry we couldn't have met under more... - It's just a tragedy.
我很难过 洛奇先生
I'm so sorry, Mr. Lodge.
谢谢 琳达 - 我很难过
Thanks, linda. - I'm so sorry.
我们今天有什么事么 - 目前还没有
What do we have today? - Nothing right away.
帕帕斯先生随时准备好见您了
Mr. Pappas would like to see you whenever...
谢谢
Thanks.
哪位
Yes.
约翰·希尔斯在六号线等待您接听
John sears on six.
你好 约翰
Hi, john.
我的天 加德纳 我很难过
Oh, god, Gardner, I'm so sorry.
节哀顺变 我不知道应该说什么了
I'm awfully sorry for your loss. I... I don't know what to say.
- 没事的 约翰 - 我很难过
It's all right, john. - I'm so sorry.
她真的是个好人 很不错的
Really, she was great. She was wonderful!
- 谢谢 约翰 - 但是...
Thanks, john. - Yeah, okay. But...
琳达 我不接电话
Linda, hold my calls.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
加德纳 加德纳
Gardner! Gardner.
你突遭不幸 我很难过
I'm so sorry to hear about your loss. Wow.
来来来
Wow. Come on back. Come on back.
弗吉尼娅 我暂时不接电话 加德纳
Virginia, hold my calls. Gardner.
挺住
Yeah.
加油
我没事 埃德 - 我知道 我知道
I'm okay, ed. - I know it. I know it.
加德纳
Gardner, look.
我只是想跟你说 我们大家跟你在一起
I just want you to know we're in there with you.
我们..
You know? We're...
- 跟你在一起 - 谢谢你 埃德
We're with you. - Thanks, ed.
好
Okay!
很高兴跟你谈了谈
I'm glad we had this talk.
有优惠券么 - 这个是面包的
Got any coupons? - This one's for the bread.
这是阿华田营养品的优惠券 能打8折 那要付多少来着
This one's for the ovaltine. It says 20% off ovaltine. How much is that?
49美分 打8折是..
Uh, 20% of 49 cents is...
就算打五折吧
Let's just call it half off.
你叫什么 - 这是尼基 他今天来给我搭把手
What's your name?  Oh, that's Nicky, and he's helping me out today.
你怎么不去上学
Why aren't you in school?
因为他逃学来帮我
'Cause he's playing hooky to help me out.
尼基 把这些东西装到篮子里好么
Nicky, will you put these things in her basket, please?
逃学 周一就逃学
Hooky. On a monday.
真是个幸运的孩子
You're a lucky boy.
12,13,14,15 第五个20美元
That's 12, 13, 14, 15, five is $20.
别忘记盖绿色的章
Don't forget your green stamps.
琳达 我不想接电话
Linda, I... no calls.
洛奇先生 抱歉 但我觉得你要接一下这个电话
Sorry, Mr. Lodge, but I thought you might want this one.
是警察局打来的
It's the police department.
我接吧
I... I'll take it.
是我
Yes.
是洛奇先生么 - 是的
Mr. Lodge? Yes.
我是盖尔·海塔尔警官
This is captain gale Hightower.
首先 您失去了妻子 请节哀顺变
Right off the bat, I ve got to tell you I'm sorry about your wife.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有别的事找你 我这有几个嫌犯 想让你来看看
The other thing is, I got a couple of guys here I'd like you to look at.
斯坦福德警方按照你的描述 昨晚抓了几个人 然后送过来了
Stamford police picked 'em up last night and sent 'em down because of your description.
他们落网了? - 别太激动 洛奇先生
They've been caught? - Now don't get too anxious there, Mr. Lodge.
只有你来确认了 才能批准逮捕
Nobody's been caught unless you say they have.
要不然他们只是路边两个相互厮斗的混混罢了
These are just two clowns picked up trying to kill each other.
那你们要我怎么办 - 来确认他们的身份
Well... What do you want me to do? Take a look at 'em.
如果你愿意劳烦跑一趟的话
You know, if you'd be so kind and all.
虽然我也很讨厌提旧事
Hate to go over old ground,
但你真的确定 歹徒闯进来的那天晚上 家里没有现金么
but you sure there wasn't any cash in the house the night of the break-in?
基本没有 怎么了
Hardly any. Why?
逮捕那俩混蛋的时候 身上可有不少票子
These two morons had a lot of dough on them when they were picked up.
还好不是刚搬进来的那帮黑鬼干的
Thank god it wasn't the schvartzes that just moved in.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你们犹太人不就是这么称呼他们的么 黑鬼
Isn't that what you jews call 'em? Schvartzes?
圣公会教徒
I'm an episcopalian.
是么 我还以为你是犹太人呢
Really? I thought you were jewish.
为什么
Why?
因为你的姓氏啊
Because of your last name.
洛奇?
Lodge?
听起来像个犹太人的姓氏
Sounded jewish.
- 圣公会教徒 - 好吧 不说了
I'm an episcopalian. - Is that right? Anyway,
我自己决定派巡逻车把你姨子接过来了
I took the liberty of having a squad car pick up your sister-in-law.
他很怕一个人独自在家待着
He was afraid to stay home alone.
一定要他参与进来么
Must he be subjected to this?
我也不知道 小伙子 你能行么
Beats me. How you doing, junior?
我可以
I'm okay.
那应该就没问题了
I think it's okay.
我觉得这样不好 因为他一直在做噩梦呢
Well, I don't think it's okay. I don't think it's okay that he's been having nightmares.
又要他见到那些家伙 我可觉得不太好
I don't think it's okay that he be asked to see these people again.
难不成你是个施虐狂么
Are you sadists down here?
行吧
All right.
那你最好在外待着 孩子 我们一会后就出来
Better wait out here, kid. We'll only be a minute.
走上来
Step up.
脸朝前
Face forward.
好了 靠墙站成一排 先生们
That's right. Line up against the wall, gentlemen.
向右转 各位先生
Turn to your right, please, gentlemen.
脸再朝前一次
Now face front again.
嘴闭紧
Keep it shut, please!
怎么样
Well?
没有
No.
女士
Ma'am?
快点说话啊 女士 你这又不是在挑墙纸
Come on, dear. You're not picking out wallpaper.
没有
No.
这些不是我们要找的人
They're not there.
我只是想看仔细点
I just wanted to be sure.
那行吧 就这样
Okay, then. That's it.
把灯关掉 路易斯 你在想什么呢
Turn that goddamn light off, lou! What are you thinking?
你在这干什么 尼基 他怎么进来了
What are you doing in here? Nicky! What is he doing in here?
抱歉 路易斯 把这孩子带出去 别让他进来
I'm sorry. Lou, take him out and keep him out, will you, please?
抱歉
Sorry about that.
我们出去吧
Let's go!
爸爸
Dad?
Dad.
你们确定么
You folks sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
我也是
Yes.
那好吧
All right, then.
- 走吧 - 那就没办法咯
Let's go. No winners tonight.
抱歉 各位
Sorry, boys.
纳吉利安女士送了一些花来 - 她是个好人
Mrs. Najarian sent some flowers. She's a fine woman.
- 我们应该请纳吉利安一家吃个饭 - 还有司陶特一家
We owe the Najarians a dinner. And the Stouts also.
不能叫他们一起来 他们两家相处不太愉快
Well, not on the same night. Uh, herb and thayer don't get along.
你觉得什么时候我们能恢复正常生活了就告诉我一声
Oh. Well, just let me know when you think it's proper to start entertaining.
我最近又重读了一些你给我的书
I was just rereading some of that book you gave me?
《生活如比赛》
Life races?
作者是...
Yeah, doctor...
伊万·马斯兰斯基博士 - 是的
Evan maslansky. Right.
你应该知道他书里说 生活就像一场场比赛
You know how he says that life is a series of races,
你赢下这场比赛 然后继续下一段生活
and you have to triumph over each one before you proceed to the next?
作者还说如果你在比赛中遇到困难
Evan says that when you find a hurdle in one of your liferaces,
要么解决困难 要么换一场比赛
you can either remove it or choose another life race.
加德纳 也许我们这是在接受生活的考验呢
Well, I just think we're being tested, Gardner.
也许吧 玛格丽特
Maybe, Margaret.
- 萝丝的不幸 这就是我们面对的困难 - 是的 我们选择换一场比赛
Rose's accident, that was a hurdle. - It was. And we chose another race.
- 如果你积蓄都花光了 就又是新的困难了 - 是啊
And when you lost your life savings, that was another hurdle.  Hmm.
我们也可以解决这个困难
And we'll triumph over this one as well.
你很坚强 加德纳 尼基也一样
Because you're strong, Gardner. And so is Nicky.
我们能一起挺过去的 对么 尼基
And we're gonna get through this together, aren't we, Nicky?
你感觉如何 儿子
How you feeling, son?
好吧
Fine.
今天真不容易
It's been a rough day.
爸爸
Dad?
你怎么能说那人不是他
How come you said it wasn't them?
你说谁
Wasn't who?
就是那些歹徒
The robbers
害死了妈妈的歹徒
who killed mom.
尼基 你看到了那些排队的人么
Nicky, did you see the line-up?
- 我看到... - 那些肯定不是我们要找的歹徒
I saw... Because that certainly was not the robbers.
绝对不是
It certainly was not.
- 我觉得.. - 孩子 我想让你明白一些事
But I thought... Young man, I want you to understand something.
人们每天走进我的办公室
People walk into my office every day,
声称他们见过我 但我从来都不记得他们
say they've met me, I don't remember them at all.
有些时候 我看到一些人 以为我认识他们
Or sometimes I see people that I think I know, and then,
然而他们却说并没有见过我
later, they tell me that we've never met.
也许他们长得像某人 他们的说话方式像某人
Maybe they look like someone else. Maybe they talk like someone else.
可能这两人是有联系的
Maybe they're even related.
- 爸爸 我看见了 - 我的意思是
But, dad, I saw. No, no, my point... my point
你到底认不认识一个人 这是说不清楚的
is that it's a very tricky business this who you know and who you don't know.
我告诉你
And I'm telling you
我仔细的看过了
that I got a good look at those clowns,
他们不是我们要找的人
and I've never seen them before.
- 米奇叔叔说 - 米奇叔叔不重要
Uncle Mitch promised that... - Uncle Mitch doesn't matter.
米奇叔叔就是个蠢蛋
Uncle Mitch is a buffoon.
这是我们自家的事 你不要跟米奇叔叔说
Now, this is a family matter, and I don't want you talking to uncle Mitch about it.
明白了么
Is that understood?
明白了
Yes, sir.
这的确是一场悲剧
It's a terrible, terrible tragedy.
神父 这对我来说是折磨
It's a torment to me, father.
我觉得我那信圣公会教的姐夫家
I feel like it's not a good environment for the child,
不适合孩子健康成长
my episcopalian brother-in-law.
你的妹妹也和孩子在一起呢
Your sister's there.
玛格丽特是个好人 但是她不太靠谱
Margaret's a good woman, but she's very scattered.
我很在意这个
It's eating at me.
这样不太好
It ain't right.
谁能替代萝丝在孩子心目中的地位呢
Who is gonna replace Rose?
我不知道 我的意思是 听你说了这些 我还是不太明白
I don't know. I mean, listening to you, I... I just don't know.
你的姐夫 不管他信什么教
And your brother-in-law, it doesn't matter who he is.
他可是孩子的父亲啊
He is the father of the boy.
我问你
Let me ask you,
那孩子有抱怨过么
Has the child complained?
简直太嘲讽了
It's a damn travesty.
萝丝就是一家人的主心骨
Rose was the heart of that family.
现在
And now,
对孩子来说 这主心骨已经不复存在了
there's no heart there for the child.
母亲离开了 上帝保佑她
The mother's gone, god bless her.
你也不能替代他的母亲啊
You're not gonna be the mother.
你是个好人
You're a good man,
但你现在是个光棍
but you're a bachelor.
那孩子有抱怨过么
Has the child complained?
没有
No.
回家去吧 米奇
Go home, Mitch.
上帝保佑你
And god bless you.
God bless you.
梅菲尔德学院
纪律严格 成就未来
为了服务祖国 为未来做好准备
不
No!
No.
啊
Please.
小宝贝?
Angel?
安迪 亲爱的 快进来
Andy, honey, you come inside.
我在捉虫
I'm just catching bugs.
- 快进来做作业 - 妈妈
You come in and do your homework. Mom!
安迪
Andy!
好的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
我和你今晚一起吃
You and I are eating alone tonight.
- 你的父亲有事... - 我不吃东西了
Your father has another... I'm not eating anymore.
你不吃东西了?
You're not, huh?
我想搬走
I want to move.
是么
Hmm, is that right?
我不想待在这了
I don't want to be here anymore.
是么
Is that right?
好吧
Well,
小伙子 我来跟你说说 你现在只是个小孩子
let me tell you something, Mister. You are a little boy.
而且还是个犯傻的小孩子
And right now, you're a very silly little boy.
等哪一天你长大了 你的意见有分量了
And the day that what you want starts counting around here
那时候你就可以去工作 挣钱养活家人
is the day that you go to work and earn money
那时候你才可以随便拒绝我了
for dinners that I can say no to.
你明天想去工作么
Do you want to go to work tomorrow?
我可以给你安排工作的
Because I can arrange that.
你同意的话 我拿起电话
You just say the word, and I'll pick up the telephone
叫卡尔格先生明天带你去上班
and tell Mr. Karger to expect Nicholas tomorrow.
需要我这么做么
Oh, shall I do that?
不用 女士
No, ma'am.
那么
Well,
我想你应该不会抱怨吃饭的问题了吧
I guess I won't hear another word out of you.
这里是伊根先生的办公室 您能不能稍等一会
Mr. Egan's office. Can you hold, please?
这里是伊根先生的办公室 - 米奇叔叔
Mr. Egan's office. Uncle Mitch?
- 您能再说一遍么 - 米奇叔叔在么
I beg your pardon? Is uncle Mitch there?
伊根先生现在在开会 需要留言么
Mr. Egan's in a meeting right now. Can I take a message?
他现在在开会 需要留言么
He's in a meeting, ma'am. Can I take a message?
我能不能在这等着他结束会议
Can I wait till he's done meeting?
我觉得你不想等那么久的 可能开会要一会儿
Well, I don't think you want to hold. It may be a while.
请问您是哪位 - 能让他打电话回来吗
Who am I speaking to? Can he call me?
如果你留下电话 我会帮你转达的
If you give me your number, I'll be happy to leave him a message.
您贵姓
What's your last name?
有什么事么
May I help you?
坐下 女士 - 先生们 他在开会
Just sit down, lady.- Gentlemen, he is in a meeting!
还是在开前几天那样的追思会么
Same meeting he's been in for the past three days?
你好啊 伙计
Hi, pal.
抱歉 洛奇先生 - 没事的 琳达
I'm so sorry, Mr. Lodge. - It's fine, Linda.
比尔 我们有空再谈吧
Uh, Bill, maybe we could pick this up some other time.
好吧 加德纳
I guess, Gardner. You bet.
这些伙计负责给我的房子做些装修工作
These men are doing some work on my house.
挺好的 很高兴见到你们
Well, that's nice. Good meeting you.
你们疯了么 就这么大摇大摆的...
What, are you crazy? You barge in here in the middle of a...
闭嘴
Shut up!
你这是耍我们么 你是想这样么
You think you can fuck us? Is that what you think?
你觉得你能耍我们么 自以为很行呢
You think you can fuck us, and that's the end of it?
我们商量好了的 你得接受这一点
We made a deal. You have to live with it.
接受我的拳头吧 你这混蛋
Live with this, you fucking hard-on.
你这家伙 把那孩子带到警察局去了
Big shot. Bring your fucking kid to the police station?
你这疯子
Mental case!
把那孩子搞定了
Take care of that kid.
我不关心你要怎么搞
I don't care what you do or how you do it.
要么你搞定
Either you do it,
要么我们自己搞定
or we do it.
至于钱嘛
And that money?
到期了就给我付过来
Fucking due and payable.
你这家伙
Big man.
疯子
Mental case.
美国南北战争时期南方邦联（支持黑人奴隶制）的非正式国歌为“我希望我在迪克西(I wish I was in Dixie)”
我希望我在迪克西！噢耶
♪ I wish I was in dixie ♪ hooray! Hooray!
我生于此地 死于此地
♪ In dixie land I'll take my stand ♪ to live and die in dixie
远走他乡 住在南方
♪ away! Away! ♪ Away down south in dixie!♪
要长那么胖应该要吃很多吧
You've got to eat a lot to get that fat.
那可是非常多
A lot!
他一走 会有个人来接替他 继续敲
Soon as he quits, somebody else picks it up and starts beating on it.
白天敲 晚上也敲
All night, all day.
我父亲说别理他们就好了
My dad says we don't show 'em nothin'.
别让他们看到你还害怕了
And you don't show 'em you're scared.
别理他们
Don't show 'em nothin'.
你舅子来电 按七号键接听
Your brother-in-law on seven.
- 米奇 - 加德纳 你找我么
Mitch. Gardner, you call me?
没有啊
No.
我这收到了一条很怪的信息啊 我的心突突的跳
I got the weirdest message. My heart skipped a beat.
说洛奇先生打电话来了 上面还附了你家的号码
Says, "Mrs. Lodge called." Has your home number on it.
我还以为是你有事找我
I thought it might've been you.
- 你在听么 - 我在
Are you there? - Yeah.
我的天 我可能在那就吓死了
My god, I could've dropped dead right there!
真的 什么“洛奇先生打电话来了”
"Mrs. Lodge called." Swear to god!
- 真是奇怪啊 - 是啊 真奇怪
That's very strange. Strange? Yeah, strange.
我要去看看你们 见一下尼基
I should come visit. Come see Nicky.
米奇
Mitch...
让我们缓缓吧
Give us a while. Huh?
挺煎熬的 我知道对你来说也挺煎熬的
It's been hard for us. And I know it's been hard for you, too.
抱歉 但是我们这段时间不希望有访客 尼基需要点时间
I'm sorry. But no visitors, just for a while. Nicky needs time.
时间
Time?
什么时间
For what, time?
再见 米奇
Bye, Mitch.
把他们组合在一起 建造一座城堡
Just snap 'em together and build a castle!
或是张凳子
Or a chair.
尼基
Nicky?
你父亲想跟你谈谈
Your father would like to have a word with you.
猴子积木很好玩的
Monkey sticks are fun!
下雨天的时候 你要待在家里
Even on rainy days, when you have to stay in.
进来
Yes?
把门关上 尼古拉斯
Shut the door, Nicholas.
坐下
Have a seat.
尼基
Nick,
我一直想让你守点
I've tried to instill in you a certain
规矩
discipline.
我觉得你的母亲太溺爱你了
Your mother indulged you, I think.
这其实没什么问题
And that's fine, up to a certain point.
她很想保护你 没什么问题
The cocoon and so forth. That's fine.
但现在我们
But now we...
我们现在来好好分析一下 现在是个什么情况
We draw the ledger, and we... we see where we are.
明白我说的话么
You understand?
明白 爸爸
Yes, sir.
我面前这位小男孩 闷闷不乐
I see a little boy who is sullen.
我面前这位小男孩 沉默寡言
I see a little boy who is frequently withdrawn,
沉浸在自己的世界里
in his own little world.
没有朋友
Little boy with no friends.
不合群
Doesn't fit in.
这些很重要 尼古拉斯 对于这些问题我们不能一笑置之
These things are important, Nicholas. We don't laugh off these things.
所以
So
我和你阿姨在找一个寄宿学校
we've been looking into sleepaway school.
在那里小伙子们会学会遵守纪律 学会合群
A place where young men learn about discipline and fitting in and...
刚会飞的幼鸟总是对鸟巢恋恋不舍 尼古拉斯 你觉得它这样好么
The fledgling always wants the nest, Nicholas, but is it good for him?
这对他来说好么 我们咨询了一些专家
Is it good for him? Well, we've consulted the experts.
我觉得不好
I think not.
所以你的阿姨玛格丽特和我决定
So your aunt maggie and I have decided
送你去 巴特尔克里克军校
that Battle Creek, the academy,
这是最好的选择
is the best solution.
下学期送你去
And starting next semester,
他们会给军校新生腾出位置
they've made room for a new plebe.
我找了些关系才得以让你顺利入学
I had to pull a few strings to get you in, but...
恭喜你啊
Congratulations.
巴特尔克里克军校 年轻人准备迎接新生活
这个要20美元
That's $20.
先生 标价牌上写的可不是20美元
Well, sir, that wasn't the price on the display.
涨价了
The price went up.
涨到20美元了?
To $20?
我觉得这个也要收20美元 对吧 玛格丽特
I believe that's $20 also, isn't it, Margaret?
是20美元
It's $20.
我能问你一个问题么
May I ask you a question?
我觉得你在别的店会有更不错的价格
I think you'll find the prices much better elsewhere.
我也这么认为
I imagine that's true.
别担心 我们会把这些放回去的
Don't worry. We'll put these back!
让吉米把这些摆回货架上
Have jimmy restock.
在不久的将来
♪ in the sweet by and by
我们将在这美丽的海岸相遇
♪ we shall meet on that beautiful shore
在不久的将来
♪ in the sweet by and by
我们将在这美丽的海岸相遇
♪ we shall meet on that beautiful shore
在不久的将来，
♪ in the sweet by and by♪
我们觉得如果这里住的都是白人
...And we understood that it was going to be all white.
我们就很愿意在这里定居
We were very happy to buy a home here.
你觉得一户黑人家庭会影响到整个社区么
Do you think a negro family moving here will affect the community as a whole?
绝对如此 - 此话怎讲
Definitely.  In what way?
我们以前住在华盛顿 我在那就遇到了一个这样的情况
We used to live in Washington, DC, and we saw a very good example of that there.
这个种族融合所带来的麻烦在于
The whole trouble with this integration business is
最后 种族间社会交往也会趋于融合
that, in the end, it probably will end up with mixing socially.
比如会有
And you will have...
我觉得他们的目标是种族通婚
Well, I think their aim is mixed marriages
黑人白人平等
and becoming equal with the whites.
但他们想要达到这个目标
But the only way they're gonna do that
是通过教育提升自己
is by education and by bettering themselves,
而不是固守他们原来的样子
not by pushing in the way they have here.
等我们拿到了那笔保险费
Soon as we get the insurance money,
一切都会好起来的
everything will be fine.
我们可以去阿鲁巴岛
We could go to Aruba.
阿鲁巴岛?那是什么地方
Aruba? Where's that?
那是在加勒比海
Oh, it's in the Caribbean.
那是荷兰的保护国
It's a Dutch protectorate.
和美国没有签订引渡协议
There's no reciprocal extradition.
我从来没有去过保护国
I've never been to a protectorate before.
我们可以从别的岛坐船过去 不留票据痕迹
We could take a boat from another island. Leave no ticket trail.
是不是可以吃上麻辣芒果食物
Well, isn't it spicy mango food?
你想吃什么美食都有 应有尽有
Oh, you can get any sort of food. Food of any description.
还可以打高尔夫 双人高尔夫球
And there's golfing. Couples golfing.
我跟萝丝去过好几次 - 那挺不错的
I went with Rose many times. Oh, that's good.
亲爱的 你可以好好放松
Darling, you could relax
作画
and paint.
展现自我
Express yourself.
我从来没有真正展现过自我
You never really express yourself.
我很爱萝丝
I loved Rose, but
但你需要别人来帮你放开自我
you need someone to help you do that.
你知道我说的这个别人是谁么
And do you know who that someone is?
那让我好好想想
Well, let me think about that.
你想啊
You do that.
玛莎·斯陶特是一位非常友好的人
Well, Martha Stout is awfully friendly.
那我来提醒你一下
Oh, well, let me try to jog your memory.
加德纳 我们早就该这么做了
We should have done this a long time ago, Gardner.
你只是困住了
You were trapped.
洛奇先生 海塔尔警官来访
Mr. Lodge, I have a lieutenant Hightower.
跟他说我不在
Tell him I'm not in.
先生 开了免提的
You're on speaker, sir.
抱歉 警官 我现在正忙着
Sorry, lieutenant. You've come at a very busy time.
很抱歉我这么仓促来访
Well, I'm sorry to drop in on you like this.
最近有了一些新情况 我想了解一下
I wanted to clear something up that's just come to light.
你近来如何
What happened to you?
就带带孩子
Horsing around with my kid.
- 孩子现在还好吧 - 是啊
He's got a mean right. He does.
调查进展如何了
So any new progress on the investigation?
其实我是想觉得有另外一个案子 你应该能帮上忙
Well, actually, I was hoping you might be able to help me with another case.
你认不认识一个叫瑞佐立的人?
You know a character named Rizzoli?
瑞佐立?没听说过
No. Rizzoli? No.
他几天前 在一辆停在收费公路上的运输车里 遇害
He got killed in a vehicular on the turnpike a couple days ago.
他叫瑞佐立 弗兰克·瑞佐立
Rizzoli. Frank Rizzoli?
从没听说过这个人
Never heard of him.
这个消息真是让我感到遗憾
I'm sorry for his loss.
你是说他离世让你遗憾?
Of life?
是啊 估计他自己也觉得很遗憾
Yeah, I guess he probably is, too.
他是为一些恶棍放高利贷的 所以我觉得他也算是死有余辜
He was a loan shark for the mob, so I wouldn't feel too bad.
我有什么能帮上忙的么
Then how can I help?
我们查阅了他的笔记本
Well, we've been going through his books.
什么记账本啊 笔记本啊
He has all these books. Notes.
都是用暗号写的
All in code.
比如
Like,
比肯小镇 剃发刮胡 8500
"Suburbicon shave and a haircut, 8,500 long."
剃发刮胡收这么多钱貌似很罕见啊
Seems like a lot of cash for a shave and a haircut.
就算是在富有的比肯镇也很少见
Even for Suburbicon.
如果你继续往下读的话 有这么一条很奇怪的记录
But if you keep reading down, it has this one very odd...
是这么说的 “从加德纳·洛奇处”拿了7000苹果
It says, "pick up package of 7,000 apples "at Gardner Lodge."
这说的是你吧
And that's your name.
我翻找了一下黄页 在其中
But we started looking through phone books, and lo and behold,
看到特伦顿附近有一家宾馆叫“加德·洛奇”
we found a hotel up near Trenton called garden Lodge.
所以 他要么是想从住在加德·洛奇宾馆里的某个人
So either he was expecting 7,000 apples
那里拿到“7000苹果”
from someone at garden Lodge,
要么就是从你这里拿到
or he expected them from you.
洛奇先生 我现在不是在审问你
Now, I'm not asking you, Mr. Lodge,
如果你问恶棍借钱
if you were into the mob for money.
如果你借了的话 不管你是没有付
But if you were, and if you didn't pay or
还是根本付不起
couldn't pay,
那
well,
也许就能解释发生在你妻子身上的不幸了
that might explain what happened to your wife.
但你说你不认识他
But you say you don't know him.
我确实不认识他
I don't know him.
那
Well,
我们继续调查
we'll keep looking.
谢谢你 警官
Thank you, lieutenant.
我们保持联系
I'll be in touch.
有一些人是完全反对种族融合的
Some of the people are definitely against integration.
他们告诉自己的孩子
And they have told my children
他们未来可能要与黑鬼结婚
That they have to marry niggers.
我的孩子甚至都不知道黑鬼是什么
And my child doesn't even know what a nigger is.
什么事
Yes?
奥罗瑞小姐 我是坎宁生命保险公司的巴德·库珀
Miss o'Rory, I'm Bud Cooper with Canyon Prop and Life.
谢谢您 库珀先生
Oh, well, thank you very much, Mr. Cooper,
但我觉得我们现在应该不用保险
but I'm quite sure we have all the insurance that we need.
是的 但其实 我不是保险推销员
I'm sure you do, but fact is, I'm not a salesman.
我是来商量一下您姐姐的保险赔偿事宜的
I'm here to discuss your sister's policy.
这个问题你恐怕和一家之主谈一下比较好
Oh, you'd have to talk to the man of the house about that.
他了解具体情况 他晚上才回来
He has all the information. He'll be back this evening.
能不能让我进来坐坐
Could... Can I just come in for a second?
那些情况我真的一点都不了解啊
Well, I don't have any of the information.
没事的 奥罗瑞小姐 我只是想来跟您聊一会儿
Oh, no, it doesn't matter, Miss O'Rory. I'd just like to chat with you for a minute.
我真的不知道 我有什么能帮到你的
Oh, I haven't the faintest idea how I can help you...
我什么都不知道啊
Since I don't have any of the information.
你说你是保险公司来的 具体是做什么的
What did you say you do for the insurance people?
我觉得我的职务全称叫做 索赔调查员
I guess my official title is claims investigator.
你也可以叫我职业挑刺员
What you might call a professional skeptic.
所以保险合同方面有什么问题么
Okay. Is there something wrong with the policy?
不不不 保险合同是没什么问题的
No, no, no! Policy seems to be all shipshape.
洛奇先生按时缴纳保险费
Yes, Mr. Lodge has been very steady with the payments.
当时接待的保险员是
Your agent...
- 埃尔金斯先生 - 是的 斯坦·埃尔金斯
Mr. Elkins? Right. Stan Elkins.
他说你们一切正常 你有见过他么
Yes, he says everything's in order. Have you met him?
没有 加德纳先生这方面的事我都不清楚
Oh, no. I don't know anything about Gardner's business affairs.
所以我觉得我没什么能帮到你的
That's why I'm afraid I can't help you.
奥罗瑞小姐 我并不关心你是否知情的问题
Well, I wouldn't worry overmuch about information, Miss o'Rory,
虽然人们都特别喜欢强调信息的重要性 但并非一直如此
because, you know, people always put "information" in quotes, but it isn't always like that.
我的意思是说 大家知道很多事 却并未意识到这一点
I mean, people just don't realize how much they know.
比如 你就正好知道保险员的名字
For instance, you happen to know your agent's name.
这类信息我这上面都好好写着呢
Mmm-hmm. I have all that information right here.
其实我对别的信息更感兴趣
I'm more interested in the other kind,
最后都可归结为一个词
which all really boils down to one word.
奥罗瑞小姐 你现在住在这么
Do you live here now, Miss o'Rory?
是的 我现在是住在这
Oh, well, I'm here now, of course.
你是临时这样 还是长期住在这
Is that a temporary or a permanent arrangement?
我觉得尼基需要母亲的关怀
I think Nicky needs a mother.
当然如此
Of course.
抱歉 我想问问你说的“一个词”是什么
Um, what was that word? Excuse me?
你刚才说的 最后都可归结为一个词
Well, you said it all boiled down to one word?
是么
Did I?
哦对
Oh! Yes!
都可以归结为一个词 巧合
Yes, it all boils down to one word, coincidence.
这种情况在歌剧里很常见  巧合嘛
That happens in the opera a lot. Coincidence.
阿伊达：意大利歌剧家威尔第作的一部歌剧
是啊 阿伊达
Yeah, sure. Aida.
塞维利亚理发师：罗西尼所作歌剧
《塞维利亚理发师》 是的 很搞笑
Uh, Barber of Seville. It's just... It gets ridiculous.
但是现实生活中巧合是很少发生的
But in real life doesn't happen that much.
如果巧合经常发生的话 那就不再是巧合了
No. I guess if it did, it would stop being a coincidence.
但是巧合和我们的保险合同无关 奥罗瑞小姐
Yeah, see, it's not the policy, Miss o'Rory.
主要谈的是这个索赔的问题
It's the claim.
这个索赔的案子中的巧合情况 就像一面面小红旗
See, a coincidence on a claim, that's like a... That's like a little red flag
给我们提个醒 让我们加以注意
that makes us sit up and take notice.
这起案子中有不少这样的小红旗
And this claim has a bunch of little red flags on it.
具体是什么样的情况呢
What kind of red flag?
没什么好担心的
Nothing to worry about.
相信我 我来只是为了拔除这些红旗 这是日常程序
Believe me, I'm just here to chase down all those little red flags. It's very routine.
我们只是需要澄清疑问
We just need to have them explained to us
再支付索赔
before we can send out a check.
没有疑问了我们会赔偿的 毫无疑问
The claim will be honored, of course.
- 挺好的 - 当然 我们来看看啊
Hmm, that's good. - Oh, sure. Let's just take a look here.
我所注意到的第一面红旗
So the first little red flag that I noticed
是三月三日
was that March 3rd,
出事前的三个月
about three months before the incident,
投保金额大幅度增加了
the amount of the whole part of the policy was substantially increased.
这不太寻常
It's kind of unusual.
你应该不知道其中原因吧
I don't suppose you know anything about that?
我知道
Mmm-hmm. I do.
那是加德纳的主意
That was Gardner's idea.
嗯 好的
It was, huh?
那好
Okay.
还有什么疑问呢 我来看看
What else have we got? We've got... Oh.
这个合同中有多项索赔请求 这个倒是很常见了
More than one claim on the policy. That's always a red flag.
你是说萝丝出车祸的时候也索赔了么
The claim from Rose's car accident?
是的 他在这上面可是狠赚了一笔呢
Yeah, he stung us good on that one.
这倒没什么问题 我们保险公司就是干这个的
Well, that's okay. That's what we're here for.
银行说他有三个月没有还房贷
The bank says he hasn't made his payments for his home loan in three months.
是这样的 情况不太好
Oh. Well, times have been a little tight around here.
加德纳做生意的时候损失了我们的全部积蓄
Gardner lost our savings when he started his own business.
是这样啊
Is that right?
我来看看还有什么
What else have we got?
这还有一点疑问
Here's another little red flag.
我此前都没有注意到这一点
I didn't even notice this one before.
大约五个月前 洛奇先生
Uh, about five months ago, Mr. Lodge
撤消了与我们签订的价值5000美元的人寿保险合同
redeemed $5,000 worth of his whole life policy with us.
我们很容易觉察到这样的细节
We always like to notice things like that.
尼基
Nicky!
尼基 回你的房间去
Nicky, get back in your room.
哪来的 滚哪去
Go back to where you came from!
离开这里
Get the hell out of here!
我很抱歉 那钱是准备用来支付尼基未来的大学学费的
I'm sorry. That money's for Nicky's college education.
是不是这钱你们买了信托基金之类的?
I guess you put it in a trust fund or something?
你想来杯咖啡么
Would you like a cup of coffee?
那真是再好不过了
That would be absolutely terrific.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我很抱歉因为这些事打扰您 但这些事是很重要的
I'm sorry to be such a pest. I mean, this stuff isn't very important,
我可以跟你讲讲我以前遇到的几起骗保案例
but I tell you, I could put you on the floor with some of the scams I've seen.
我想起那些事都会笑出声
I've got to smile just thinking about them.
几年前有一个人
I mean, I had this one guy couple of years ago,
他自己的服装店烧毁了 要求赔偿
he put in a claim for his clothing store burned down.
你肯定会觉得这故事难以置信
You're not gonna believe this.
我们在现场发现了几个汽油桶 上面写有“尤拉·梅”
We find a couple of gas cans in there with Eulah May printed on them.
这是他妻子的名字
It's his wife's name.
这是他从自己的游艇上搞来的
It's the name of his pleasure boat where he got the cans from.
我估计他是觉得这些铝制桶子应该会一起烧掉吧 不知道他是怎么想的
I guess he thought those aluminum cans were gonna burn up or something. I don't know what he thought!
还有那些汽车保险案 谢谢
And cars. Thank you.
你肯定难以置信 人们是怎么对待自己的车的
You wouldn't believe what people do to their cars
就因为出了点小毛病
just because something's a little wrong with the transmission.
他们就觉得能敲保险公司的竹杠
They figure they can fleece us for the whole thing.
当报废车处理啊 然后报失啊
Sell 'em for scrap, report 'em stolen.
那些汽车修理厂的人我们都会打点好的
See, but the body shop guy knows we pay a bounty for those things.
就这周 这边半个街区的人都来找我们的麻烦
Mmm. Yeah, I mean, just this week, half your block tried to tap us
就因为你边上的这位新邻居
for homeowner's because of your new neighbors.
你敢信么 就因为来了位新邻居
Can you believe it? How about them neighbors!
噢 抱歉
Oh, excuse me.
要是你像我一样在这行干久了
You've been in this business long as I have,
就会对这种事有敏锐的嗅觉
you develop a nose for hanky-panky.
每起案件仿佛就像有味道似的
'Cause it smells, you know?
那种淡淡的味道
It's got this faint aroma.
有些闻起来很不妙 有些就很正常 你懂我的意思么
This smells bad. That smells good. You know what I mean?
但是这个嘛
But this one?
这个案子嘛
This particular case here?
闻起来没有那种淡淡的味道 - 谢天谢地
Does not have that faint aroma. - Thank goodness for that.
而是恶臭难闻
Nah, this one stinks.
我从刚下高速路来这的路上就有这种感觉了
This one... I've been smelling this one since I got off the turnpike.
我的天 简直太臭了
Jesus, does it stink!
你跟加德纳睡过吧
You sleep with Gardner, do you?
你说什么
I beg your pardon!
我知道这跟我没什么关系
Well, you know, that's none of my business,
但我得跟你们说 这种事是遗臭万年的
but I've got to tell you, that kind of nonsense, it can come back and haunt you down the road.
要是你们想办法把她弄死的话
If you killed her, I mean.
你怎么敢
How dare you
我的姐姐尸骨未寒 你来我家里开这种玩笑
come into this home when my sister is dead
还扯什么旗子和理发室的淡
and make jokes about flags and the barber of seville!
我保证 奥罗瑞女士 我来绝对不是开玩笑
Oh, I assure you, Miss o'Rory, I am anything but joking.
我觉得 根据我的经验 没有哪个蠢货
You see, in my experience, nobody's stupid enough
会在杀妻之前提高投保金额的
to increase their insurance policy just before they kill their wife.
我要告诉你一点 加德纳·洛奇肯定不是蠢货
If there's one thing you can be sure of, it's that Gardner Lodge isn't stupid.
我同意 库珀先生 那这么说来 你自己是完完全全的错了
Oh, I agree. So you've just proved yourself wrong, Mr. Cooper.
这些是我编的
I made it up.
你编的? - 我编的
You made it up? I made it up.
他没有增加萝丝的投保金额 我只是钓鱼而已
He didn't take out more insurance on Rose. I was just fishing.
我调查每起案子都这样 我是去钓鱼的
I do it on every claim. I go fishing.
我跟你说 这次我可算抓住一处马脚了
And you know what? This time I caught a whopper.
什么
What?
你用的是"我们"
You said "we."
你说什么
What?
你说的是“加德纳失去了我们的全部积蓄”
"We lost our savings "when Gardner tried to start his own business."
你说的是我们 而不是他们
"We lost our," not "they lost their."
赶紧走人 要不然我报警了
I think you should leave before I call the police.
你报警啊
Call them.
我跟你说 我们去街那头
Hell, you know what? Let's just walk down the street.
那一头就有不少警察
There's a dozen of them standing a block away.
你滚出我的房子 - 你的房子
You get out of my house. Your house?
滚出去 滚出去
Oh! Get out! Get out. Get out, you!
我爱我的姐姐 我爱她的孩子
I loved my sister, and I love her son!
你也爱她的丈夫吧
You love her husband, too?
跟洛奇先生说 我晚上会再来的
You tell Mr. Lodge I'll be back this evening.
我们今晚可以聊聊
We can have a chat about it then.
你今晚请个假 - 你说什么
You're taking the night off. What?
你今晚请个假 我有更重要的事要派你去做
You're taking the night off. I've got more important things for you to do.
你疯了吧 兄弟
You're crazy, man.
斯坦霍普会来给你打掩护的 我们有正事干
I got Stanhope to come in and cover for you. We've got business.
好好好 什么事 说话别这么大声
All right. What is it? And don't talk so loud.
这家伙很难缠
This guy's a fucking hard-on, is what it is.
他昨晚挂了我的电话
He hung up on me last night.
他不在乎我们了 我觉得他这是准备搞我们
He doesn't care. I think he's getting ready to fuck us.
他搞不了我们
He can't fuck us.
这就对了嘛
That's right!
门卫
我跟你说 这是那家伙最后一次耍我们了
I'm telling you, this is the last time that clown's gonna ignore us.
所以我要你今晚请假
That's why you're taking the night off.
把那女的和小孩都搞定喽
Take care of the kid and the lady.
等他回来了 给他好好提个醒
Give him something to think about when he gets home.
他妈的又搞两个人? 我觉得还是不要吧
Two more fucking people? I don't know if I can get into that.
我跟你说 你没得选
I'm telling you, you ain't got any choice.
要么我们出手 要么等着他搞我们
It's either that, or he fucks us!
那家伙不理我们 不回复我们
The guy don't respond, he don't respond.
那可是两条人命啊 兄弟
Two people, man!
听着 如果你连一个女的和一个孩子都搞不懂
Look, if you can't take care of a kid and a lady,
你知道这意味着什么吗
you know what that means?
那估计你他妈的就是个废物了
It means you're a fucking liability.
加德纳 我很抱歉 真的很抱歉
Gardner, I'm sorry. I'm so, so sorry.
我很爱你 求求你别生我的气
I love you so much. Please don't be angry with me.
怎么回事
What happened?
- 你是洛奇先生 - 是我
Mr. Lodge? Yes.
我觉得 你姨子应该跟你提了我的事吧
I believe your sister-in-law might have mentioned me to you?
是的
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好 女士
Hello, ma'am.
你好
Hello.
走这边
Right this way.
外面真是人声鼎沸啊
It's quite a commotion out there.
是啊 我知道 请坐吧
Yes, I know. Have a seat.
全镇的人都来了 扔石头 扔垃圾 你看到了么
Whole town's out there, throwing rocks and garbage. Did you see that?
我看到了
I saw.
那些人估计还以为自己在密西西比州呢
All those people, you'd think we're in Mississippi.
请别拉开窗帘
Please, just keep the curtains closed.
行 可能还是不开为好
Yeah, that's probably a good idea.
你对我的那些指控...
Now, what are these accusations...
奥罗瑞小姐 如果不是很麻烦的话
Miss o'rory, I tell you, a cup of coffee would be really terrific,
我想来一杯咖啡
if it isn't too much trouble.
- 不麻烦 - 谢谢
No trouble. Thank you.
我今天挺辛苦的 我直入主题吧
Look, I've had a long day. So let's just get right to the point.
你杀了你的妻子
You killed your wife.
你想骗保费 我要插一手
You want to collect. I want a piece of the action.
我不想跟你一直扯些没用的 我也不打算跟你谈判之类的
I don't want to talk about this for a long time. I'm not gonna negotiate.
我今天已经很累的
I've had a long day.
我也不想听你拒绝我
I'm not gonna hear any denials.
告诉我 行还是不行
Just tell me, yes or no.
你想怎么样 分一部分钱?
What do you want? You want some of the money?
我全都要了
I want all of it.
全部都要
All of it.
要么你就直接进监狱了 兄弟
Or you go straight to jail, pal.
我可以马上走出去 叫六个警察过来
I could walk outside and have six police officers here in no time.
咖啡来了
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
你无路可走
You don't have any choice.
我就坐在这 等你自己想明白现在究竟是什么情况
I'm just gonna sit here and wait for you to figure that out for yourself.
可以吧
All right?
如果我们确实
If we did
杀了我的妻子
kill my wife,
那你为什么不觉得
what makes you think
我不能连你一起杀了呢
I wouldn't kill you, too?
洛奇先生
Mr. Lodge.
你疯了么
Are you crazy?
你以为我是唯一一个能分辨出
Do you think that I'm the only investigator
骗保案的调查员么
that knows how to read a claim for fraud?
如果一位调查员
Do you have any idea what happens
在调查这么疑点重重的案子的时候突然死了 你知道会发生什么吗
when an investigator that's working on a claim like this dies?
你骗保险公司骗得还不够多么
Haven't you fucked with the insurance company enough?
相信我
Believe me,
如果我遭遇了什么不测
if anything happens to me...
你就会陷入很深很深的...
You're in deep, deep, deep...
离那辆车远点 快走
Get away from that car! Get out of there!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
滚远点
Get back away from there!
在床下面
Under the bed!
你在咖啡里放了什么
What did you put in the coffee?
就是碱液而已
Just lye!
就放了一点碱液
Just a little bit of lye.
我回来前别走动
Don't move until I get back.
救命 救命
Help, help, help...
米奇叔叔 你要救救我 他们要杀了我
Uncle Mitch, you've got to help! They're gonna kill me!
尼基 你在说什么呢
Nicky! What are you talking about?
他们要杀了我
They're gonna kill me!
你留在那 我...
You stay right there. I'll...
米奇叔叔 米奇叔叔
Uncle Mitch? Uncle Mitch!
尼基
Oh, Nicky.
我把他尸体塞他车里了
I put him in his car.
瞒不住了 玛格丽特
It's falling apart, maggie.
结束了
It's over.
我们得离开这儿
We're gonna have to leave.
尼基在哪
Where's Nicky?
他打电话给米奇了
He talked to Mitch.
尼基
Nicky?
亲爱的
Honey?
你得吃点东西
You have to have something to eat.
不能空着肚子就去睡觉
Can't go to bed on an empty stomach.
尼基
Nicky?
那好吧
Well, all right.
随你的便吧
Suit yourself.
我来吃
I'll eat it.
亲爱的
Angel!
至少喝点牛奶吧
At least have some milk.
那不是我的错
It's not my fault.
谁说是你的错呢
Why would anybody say it was your fault?
我们不怪你
You're not to blame.
加德纳跟我 要走了
We're gonna go away, Gardner and me.
你去过阿鲁巴岛么
Have you ever been to Aruba?
那是荷兰的
It's a protectorate.
受保护领地
That's Dutch.
那里会有异域的食物
There's all kinds of exotic foods.
还能一起打高尔夫
And couples golf.
嗨
Hi.
出来啊 小子
Come on, kid.
你他妈的是谁
Who the fuck are you?
他妈的
Motherfucker!
去死吧
Die!
出来吧 尼基
Come on, Nicky.
孩子 出来吧
Come on, son. Come out of there.
真是个好孩子
Attaboy. Attaboy.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
都结束了
It's all over.
来吧 躲进去
Go on. Go inside.
别发出噪音 明白了么
Now, you don't make a noise, you understand?
你是个好孩子 尼基 会没事的
You're a good boy, Nicky. You're gonna be fine.
谁把你当亲儿子一样看待
Who loves you like a son?
是你
You do.
好孩子 尼基
Attaboy, Nicky.
现在你
Okay, now you...
拿着这个
You take this.
好
Okay.
你是个好孩子
You're a good boy.
你好
Hello?
你真是个废物啊
You're becoming a liability.
你要去哪啊
Where you going?
你懂的
Oh, you know,
就出去骑个车
just out for a ride.
你回家的时候会有惊喜的
Surprise for you when you get home.
你干了什么
What did you do?
你要把钱付给我们
You're gonna pay us that money.
你干了什么 - 你要把钱付给我们
What did you do? You're gonna pay us that money.
What did you do? You're gonna pay us that money!
起火了
Fire Help.
救命
Help!
玛格丽特
Maggie?
Maggie!
玛格丽特
Maggie?
尼基
Nicky?
把枪给我
Give me that.
这些人禽兽不如
These people are animals.
他们夺走了我们的一切
They took everything from us.
他们杀了你
They took your
玛格丽特阿姨
aunt maggie,
米奇 杀了你的妈妈
Mitch, your mom.
我要你远离那个黑人男孩
I want you to stay away from that colored boy.
你听明白了么
You hear me?
你会报警么
Are you gonna call the police?
我们谈完了
I'll call the police
我会报警的
when we finish our talk.
现在
Now,
这些禽兽不如的家伙夺走了我们的一切
these animals took everything from us.
我们要保持...
And we need to make sense...
是你 这都是你干的
It was you. You did all of this.
你觉得自己知道什么
What do you think you know,
小伙子?
big man?
这些事我都很清楚
Because I know a lot of things.
成年人就是这样
That's the case with being a grownup.
你必须做出决定
You have to make decisions.
决定怎么样对我们这个家最好
Decisions like what's best for the family.
谁有用
Who's being helpful.
谁是累赘
Who's a liability.
你应该知道累赘这个词的意思吧 尼基
You know what that word means, Nicky?
你看这些人
You see, these men
杀了你的妈妈
killed your mom.
然后他们回来
And then they came back.
可以说是 杀人灭口吧
Tie up loose ends, so to speak.
他杀了你的阿姨玛格丽特
He killed your aunt maggie.
捅死了你的叔叔米奇
Stabbed your uncle Mitch.
好像他们还没杀够
As if that weren't bad enough,
他杀了你
then he killed you.
在厨房里杀了你
Right here in the kitchen.
然后我开枪杀了他
Then I shot him.
他也捅了我几刀
Oh, he cut me a few times.
也许这儿
Maybe here.
这儿
Here.
反正是没什么生命危险的伤
Nothing too life-threatening.
警官
"Officer,
我竭尽全力想要救下我的孩子
I did everything I could to save my boy.
但他深受重伤
"His injuries were just too great.
唉
"Well,
他现在和他妈妈在一起了
"he's with his mama now.
他成了天堂里的小天使
"He's the littlest angel in heaven."
那就是你
That's you.
小天使
Little angel.
或者
Or...
我们一起打电话报警
...we call the police together.
告诉他们 这些人杀了我们的家人
We tell them how these men killed our family.
能活下来真是幸运
How we feel lucky to be alive.
尼基 你去过阿鲁巴岛么
You ever heard of Aruba, Nicky?
我们会申请
We'll tell the papers
不要那些保险赔款
we don't want that insurance money,
但我们要用这些钱重建我们的生活
but we're gonna use it to rebuild our lives.
我们会去
Our lives
一个很远的地方生活
far away
我们会淡忘这里
from the memory of this place.
我们坐上飞机 去阿鲁巴岛
And then we get on a plane and go to Aruba.
在岛上买个大房子
And we buy a big house on the beach.
重新开始
And we start over.
所以 小伙子
So, big man,
我的大小伙子
my big grown man,
你要做出这样的重大决定了
you've got a big decision to make.
好好想想吧
Take your time.
今天是周日
It's sunday.
比肯镇的周日
Sunday in Suburbicon.
我们有的是时间
We've got all the time in the world.
- 谢谢 - 没事的 女士
Thank you. Of course, ma'am.
一位警察被打的头破血流
One policeman got his head busted open.
一辆救火车在拉法叶街发生车祸 一人身亡
And a fire truck hit and killed a man down on Lafayette street.
另外三位还是四位伤员送往了医院
And three or four others ended up in the hospital.
还有萝丝·洛奇 唉
And Rose Lodge! This...
迈尔斯一家搬到这之前从没出过这样的事
None of this ever happened before the Mayers moved here.
这是一个平静的小镇 你有没有听说过什么关于迈尔斯一家的谣言?
This is a peaceful town. Have you heard any rumors about the Mayers?
听过很多很多谣言
Oh, dozens and dozens of rumors.
听说全国有色人种协进会给他们提供财力支持
Oh, that he was being paid by the NAACP.
可能背后有共党分子操纵他们 可能有犹太人插手
That the reds were behind it, that the jews were behind it,
形形色色的组织给他们撑腰
that this group and that group were behind it.
有各种各样的谣言
There were all kinds of rumors.
我觉得有些谣言是故意传的 有些只是人们大惊小怪罢了
I guess some of them were being spread deliberately. Some were just the result of hysteria.
我不是觉得应该压迫他们
I don't feel that they should be oppressed.
但我搬到这里
But I moved here.
一个主要原因
One of the main reasons
就是这是一个完全由白人组成的社区
was because it was a white community.
发生在杰拉尔德·麦克洛伊
And that......The story of Gerald Mccloy
这位小男孩 身上的奇怪故事
and the strange thing that happened to that little boy.
他们说这一切都开始于杰拉尔德两岁的时候
They say it all started when Gerald was two.
二岁的孩子差不多刚刚学会说话 至少他们中的大部分都是这样的
That's the age kids start talking. Least most of them do.
当他开始说话的时候 你知道他说了什么吗
Well, when he started talking, you know what he said?
他说出来的不是词语 而是
He didn't talk words. He went, "boing, boing,"
哔哔
instead.